A Guide to the Delta Omega Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha, (1921, 1988)
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
A Guide to the Delta Omega Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority Inc., 1921, 1988
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1976-79
1000 items
Records documenting the establishment of the Delta Omega chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority at Virginia State University(then the Virginia Normal and Industrial Institute). Delta Omega was the first chapter founded in the south east region.
The Delta Omega Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority Inc.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority was formed at Howard University in 1908. The original nine members were Ethel Hedgeman Lyle, Marjorie Hill, Peselah Lillie Burke, Margaret Flagg Holmes, Lavinia Norman, Marie Woolfolk Taylor, Lucy Slowe and Anna E. Brown. From this group Ms. Lucy Slowe was selected as the first Basileus.
The Delta Omega Chapter was the first to be formed in the South Atlantic Region, and also the fourth graduate chapter established on the campus of Virginia State College. Soror Nellie Quander, the deputy Organizer for the East, set up this chapter. This Chapter was organized February 6, 1921. The chapter members were Louise Stokes (Hunter), Pauline Simms (Puryear), Mae Hatchett (Seabrooks), Ester Tate, and Edna Colson. All of these Sorors except Sorors Tate and Colson had been members of the Alpha Chapter at Howard University. (The History of The South Atlantic Region of Alpha Kappa Alpha written by committee of history of the Southern Atlantic Region, chairman Clarissa K. Dillard appointed 1948)
Scope and Content Information
The records of the Delta Omega Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha span the year 1921 through 1988. This includes correspondence and reports as well as issues of the Ivy Leaf.
These papers reflect how this chapter was organized and how they sought to carry out the mission of the Sorority. Issues such as sisterhood, empowerment and service not only to the campus but to the community as well.
Additional materials about Delta Omega may be found in the Colson/ Hill Family Papers, accession number 1965-13, boxes 57, 57a, 57b, in addition, the Alice and Henry Colson Jackson Papers Accession # 195-13a and in the records of the Petersburg Epicureans, unarranged.
Series Description
Series I. Chapter Records Some idea of how the chapter operated and how it was structured. The minute book for 1939-1941 also contains information regarding committees and chapter projects. Included in this series are membership roster, transfer and initiation. It also contains minutes and reports about issues and projects at the Regional and National level.
Series II. Chapter Projects Because Alpha Kappa Alpha is a service oriented organization they are committed to trying to improved not only the leadership skills of other women who are members, but also to the community. This series documents of some of those activities.
Series III. Printed Programs, Handbooks, minutes of some of the A. K. A. Boule, Songs and Ivy Leaf magazines.
Series IV. Photographs Several photo's of members of Delta Omega and debutantes for the year 1951.
Contents List
- Chapter Records
  - Minute Book 1939-1941
  - Constitution and By Laws 1945,1956 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Position Bond 1954-1957 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Budgets 1955-1957 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Epistoleus Reports 1954,1957 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Membership Roster No Date (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Initiations 1957 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Transfers 1951-1957 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Basilei and Graduate Transfers 1964 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - A Brief History of A.K.A No Date (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Minutes-Regional Conference 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Minutes-First Basilei Conference 1954 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Minutes-Ninth Basilei Conference 1962 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Report- Regional Director 1956 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Committee 1955-1957 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Committee,Assignments 1959-1960 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Comittee-Awards 1948-1950 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Committee-Bazaar No Date (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Committe-Conference 1964 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Committee-Community Service 1955 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Committee-Hospitality 1960 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Committee-Founders Day 160, 1966 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Committee-National Projects No Date (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Committee-Program (Box-folder 1:23)
  - The A.K.A Patroness Group 1946,1950 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Chapter Records (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Correspondence, Corey B. Preston 1956 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Correspondence, National Office 1954-1957 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Correspondance, General 1921-1938 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Correspondance, General 1950,1955 (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Correspondance, General 1956 (Box-folder 1:30)
  - Meeting Notices 1957,1968 (Box-folder 1:31)
  - Thank You Notes 1955-1960 (Box-folder 1:32)
- Chapter Projects
  - National Project, Vocational Guidance 1926 (Box-folder 2:33)
  - National Project, Vocational Guidance (Box-folder 2:34)
  - Correspondance, Leadership Conference 1964 (Box-folder 3:35)
  - Correspondence, Leadershp Conference 1964 (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Second Leadership Conference (Delegates) 1964 (Box-folder 2:37)
  - Second Leadership Conference (Delegates) 1964 (Box-folder 2:38)
  - Second Leadership Conference (Delegates) 1964 (Box-folder 2:39)
  - Second Leadership Conference (Delegates) 1964 (Box-folder 2:40)
  - Second Leadership Conference (Program) 1964 (Box-folder 2:41)
  - Second Leadership Conference (Reports) 1964 (Box-folder 2:42)
  - Debutantes 1954 (Box-folder 2:43)
  - Debutantes 1954 (Box-folder 2:44)
  - Debutantes, List Of 1954 (Box-folder 2:45)
  - Debutantes Ball, account 1954 (Box-folder 2:46)
- Printed
  - Program- Unveiling Ceremonies 1967 (Box-folder 2:47)
  - Program, Guides 1956 (Box-folder 2:48)
  - Songs No Date (Box-folder 2:49)
  - Ceremony, Founders Day (Box-folder 2:50)
  - Award National Projects Fund 1956 (Box-folder 2:51)
  - Newsletter, Regional 1955 (Box-folder 2:52)
  - Newsletter, Delta Omega 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2:53)
  - Newsletter, Ivy Leaf 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2:54)
  - News-Clippings No Date (Box-folder 2:55)
- Photographs
  - National Meeting No Date
  - Members No Date
  - Brown, Naomi 1951- Debutantes Ball
  - Butler, Delors 1951-Debutantes Ball
  - Chapman, Edna 1951-Debutantes Ball
  - Douglas,Delores 1951-Debutantes Ball
  - Jones, Gean 1951-Debutantes Ball
  - Morton, Jean 1951-Debutantes Ball
  - Reese, Dorothy 1951-Debutantes Ball
  - Saunders, Carinne 1951-Debutantes Ball
  - Debutantes Ball 1954
  - Debutantes Ball 1954
  - Debutantes Ball ca 1960's
  - Debutantes Ball No Date
  - Debutantes Ball No Date
  - Printed, Programs, minutes of some Alpha Kappa Alpha and Ivy Leaf Magazines for (1940,1943-1945). In addition there are copies of the A.K.A Yearbooks, 1952, 1980, and a history of the South Atlantic Region of Alpha Kappa Alpha (Box 4)
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 18-June 1940 (AKA Papers)
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine, Volume 19-March 1941, June 1941, December 1941
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 20-March 1942, June 1942, September 1942
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 21-March 1943, June 1943 (AKA Papers), September 1943, December 1943
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 22-March 1944, June 1944 (AKA Papers), September 1944, December 1944
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 23-March 1945 (AKA Papers), June 1945, September 1945, December 1945
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 23-March 1946, June 1946
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 25-June 1947, September 1947
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 26-Missing
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 27-June 1949, September 1949, December 1949
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 28-March 1950, June 1950, December 1950
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 29-June 1951
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 30-March 1952, June 1952, September-December1952
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 31-March 1953, June 1953, September 1953, Decmber 1953
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 32-March 1954, June 1954, September 1954, December 1954
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 33-March 1955, September 1955, December 1955
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 34-March 1956, June 1956, September 1956, December 1956
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 35-March 1957, June 1957, September 1957, December 1957
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 36-March 1958, June 1958, September 1958
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 37-March 1959, June 1959, October 1959, December 1959
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 38-March 1960, June 1960, September 1960
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 39-February 1961, April 1961, December 1961, March 1962, June 1962, September 1962
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 40-March 1963, June 1963, September 1963, December 1963, March 1964, June 1964, September 1964, November 1964, February-March 1965, June 1965
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 41-Decmber 1965, September 1965, December 1967
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 42-February-March 1966, June-July 1966, December 1966
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 43-February 1967, May 1967, September 1967, November 1967
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 44-February 1968, May-June 1968, September-October 1968, November-December 1968
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 45-March 1969, May-June 1969, September-October 1969, November-December 1969
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 46-Spring 1970, Summer 1970, Fall 1970, Winter 1970
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 47-March 1971, May 1971, September 1971, November 1971
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 48-February 1973, May 1972, Fall 1972, Winter 1972
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 49-Fall 1973
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 50-Spring 1974, Summer 1974, Fall 1974, Winter 1974
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 51-Summer 1975, Fall 1975, Winter 1975
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 52-Spring 1976
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 53-Summer 1976
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 54-1977
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 55-(In Alice Jackson Papers) Summer 1978
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 56-Winter 1979
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 57-Summer 1980, Fall 1980, Winter 1980
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 58-Spring 1981, Summer (In A.J Papers), Fall (In A.J Papers), Fall, Winter (In A.J Papers)
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 59-Spring 1982, Summer 1982, Fall 1982, Winter 1982
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 60-Spring 1983, Fall 1983, Winter 1983
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 61-Spring 1984, Summer 1984, Winter 1984
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 62-Summer 1985, Fall-Winter 1985, Winter 1985
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 63-Spring 1986, Summer 1986
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 64-Spring 1987, Summer 1987
    - Ivy Leaf Magazine,Volume 65-Spring 1988